ANATOLY YAKOVENKO

aeyakovenko@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software developer with over 10 years of experience in embedded operating systems, developing <u>patents</u>, leading projects and contributing to large groups including <u>Linux Kernel</u>, with a focus on performance and optimization for Qualcomm ARM and DSP processors.

SKILLS

Hardware and Systems

 Embedded Operating Systems, Linux Kernel, Android, Qualcomm MSMs, System MMUs, ARM, Hexagon DSP

Languages and Tools

• C, C++, Haskell, Lua, Make, Python, Ruby, Git, Perforce, GDB, Trace32

WORK EXPERIENCE

Qualcomm, San Diego CA

Senior Staff Engineer, 2012 to Present Staff Engineer, 2008 - 2012 Senior Engineer, 2006 - 2009 Engineer, 2003 - 2006

- Achieved 10x performance improvement in subsystem communication via FastRPC, a bridge between the DSP co-processor and ARM processor for high performance applications. Ported to Windows, Qnx, Android <u>Linux Kernel</u>. Patents: 20140136817, 20140096148
- IDL (Interface Description Language) compiler for <u>Hexagon SDK</u>
- Dynamic linker for loading dynamic processes on Qualcomms embedded DSP OS
- Dynamic module framework for loading shared objects on DSP from the application processor
- Capability based application framework for BREW (Qualcomm's Mobile Operating System)
- Component Object Model IPC (Inter-Process Communication) implementation for BREW
- IDL compiler with C/C++/Lua backends for BREW IPC
- Elf manipulator with a DSL (Domain Specific Language) in Lua
- System call trace tool for BREW IPC with a Lua DSL.
- Build system plugins for unit testing and verifying code coverage
- Declarative full featured object library for C with C++ compatible v-tables, in less then 500 bytes of RO arm object code
- Prototype and test generation tool for rapid development of BREW components

- Network components using SIP/HTTP/RTP and proprietary standards for QChat push to talk service
- High performance logging tools to handle tens of thousands of transactions per second from many networked components

Alescere LLC, Lisle IL

Co-Founder, 2001 to 2003

- Founding member of Alescere, a VOIP startup
- SIP and RTP protocol stacks, and server components for a VoIP system for small businesses

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Research Assistant, 2003

- Web server that supports QoS for HTTP requests
- Probabilistic scheduler for the Linux kernel
- Roaming protocol for 802.11a/b networks for NetBSD

Personal Research

• Neural Networks, Genetic Algorithms, Markov Models, and Bayes Inference Algorithms

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2003